testing Ai generate subs, please disable if uncomfortable. warning is removed at 0:15
Hi.
I came on live.
Hi. Hi.
I was bored
so I turned on the live.
Ah,
Since you've only been seeing heavy makeup lately,
seeing light makeup like this must be really
awkward.
It's awkward for me too.
Something
feels missing.
Like I should do something more, I have this
compulsion now.
Doing the concert this time,
I've been doing heavy makeup for days straight so
Wait a second
I haven't eaten dinner yet.
I kept sleeping
and monitoring
then sleeping again
it was just a loop of this.
But I should have gone out today the weather looked so nice.
I lost a lot of weight.
Really
I'm so upset.
So I'm going to gain it back.
Now
um
now
back to
my original
true self
I plan to go back
I should eat now.
Hmm.
Behind the scenes of the wrap party
It wasn't until too
late
but we were there for a while yesterday since our
concert ended early.
The wrap party
started
early and
yesterday
for a long time
ah
what was it?
The dancers
and the unnies
It wasn't just
unnies there were more younger ones
but anyway
with the dancers
together
talking like this
and all
we stayed for quite a while
all together.
Right? It's amazing that I stayed late. I'm surprised too.
I kept
making mistakes. No, I mean our dancer unnies
Ah they aren't unnies.
I kept saying it but
they aren't unnies.
So this
long nail
by tomorrow
I have to take it off.
Because of another shoot the day after tomorrow.
To a nude tone
my nails
I have to change them.
Well.
Why are the comments so fast today?
You think something changed?
It's because I barely wore
any makeup today.
Really
at the concert
really
there were so many new people who started liking us
Mm.
I think there were a lot of people seeing us for the first time
or who just started liking us
especially at this concert.
I was really
surprised you came so prepared
Flover
and I was really
so
surprised you knew it all.
But for this
concert
really
should I call it behind-the-scenes stories?
I feel like there are a lot of
little behind-the-scenes stories.
For this
concert
first of all
from the beginning stages
we
participated a lot. Last time for the setlist and things like that
we left it mostly
to the company
but if we did that last time
for this concert
we felt like
we wanted to show
a concert vibe
that Flover hasn't
seen before.
Since we have a lot of
bright songs
the setlist
was mainly
focused on
a bright mood
is what we felt
so we
wanted to
include
a variety of colors
in one
concert.
We thought about that
and this is something
we always
agreed on
because we really
don't have many dark songs either.
But doing this full album
there were some songs
with a dark mood
so
we thought
this might be the only time
we could do this
and that's why
we tried putting together a colorful setlist.
And the members
always talked about
wanting to try wearing uniforms and stuff
that's what we talked
about.
Well
it's a concert
and we felt that
just filling it
with really princess-like things
was too
something
too
Since we have a concert every single year
wearing princess clothes every year makes it feel like
we're doing the exact same concert
so we thought
it might be a picture you've already seen
so for a long time
we wanted to start with Rewind.
The stage
the opening
we wanted to start with Rewind.
But doing Rewind
um
acapella
with Jiwon and
Hayoung unnie hitting
the high notes
to really set the mood
we wanted to start it like that.
For the concert
that's what we thought
and this was really
talked about a long time ago
starting with a Rewind opening
but to beat Rewind
I mean to have a proper build-up
we needed a climax but we didn't have a song
that could top Rewind for that peak
so we were like ah
what do we do what do we do but
with Attitude and
songs like that coming out
the setlist
came together.
Honestly
there was some pushback from the company again this time.
About starting with Rewind
they said if we start with Rewind then Supersonic and
Like You Better
since Rewind is so intense
they were almost 100% unsure
if the mood would
flow well.
they were almost 100% unsure
So
since a long time ago
I really
wanted to start with Rewind so badly
so I really
worked hard to convince them.
That we have to start with Rewind.
Start with Rewind and then connect it to Supersonic
so that new
fans
as well as everyone
can hear a song they know
right after.
And then
since Supersonic and
Like You Better connect well too
do Like You Better next.
And since Like You Better
is now
with a live band
do Love Disaster next.
But up to this point
these are songs you've seen very recently so
we needed a song you haven't seen before to pop up right here.
A song you
haven't seen in a long time.
I really
worked hard
to convince them
about this
and that's how
we put together
this first setlist.
For Airplane Mode
um
the members
the company and all of us including me
debated a lot about whether to include it because
we were worried if we could
put it all together
in such a short amount of time
and for Air- what
Airplane Mode
I mean
after Love Disaster
people had mixed opinions on whether it would fit
Anyway
since Airplane Mode
we would have been running so much anyway right?
Rewind, Attitude
Supersonic, Like You Better, Love Disaster
running through all five songs
could we still run for
Airplane Mode?
Would we have the stamina?
We wondered that but
all the members agreed that if we do Airplane Mode
we have to do the choreography
and if it doesn't have choreography
we should take it out.
The members felt this is a song that needs choreography
so it was unanimous
that it needs choreography to be put in the setlist.
With that thought
even if it meant
pushing ourselves a bit
we did the choreography
for Airplane Mode.
Really
um
Skyrunner
ah should we go through them one by one like this?
Overall we thought we should cut down on our talking time
because
last time we had
a challenge time in the middle of the stage right?
Um
since it's a concert
doing things like that made all the members feel
like it was a bit of a fan meeting
it's a concert
so we felt it was right to show more performances.
Last time
we had this vibe of let's just do everything
the fans would like
but this time
we wanted to show fromis_9's performances.
That was our thought.
So
that vibe was great too but
for fan meeting things
we can do them
when we have a fan meeting
and for covers and solo stages
right now
it's a concert so
since it's our concert let's show our songs.
That was our thought
so instead of covers
or other
challenges like that
we filled it with our songs
and our stages instead.
And
we cut down
the talking time.
Doing stages
without
talking feels a bit more like
we're enjoying
the performance.
When we take a break during talking time
the excitement
that had been building up
slightly cools down right?
Let's lessen
that cooldown.
So Flover
could follow along with our concert's vibe
that's why
Chaeng unnie
strongly argued
to cut down the talking
and all the members agreed
so we did that.
Ah it's hot
The reason I keep touching my hair is because it's at an awkward length right now
I tried to put hair pieces in but I didn't have any at home
Ah it's driving me crazy.
Anyway
so
we cut down a lot of the talking
and doing so many stages
back to back like that
ah
it was really
honestly quite exhausting. Wow
I guess we were a bit too ambitious.
We should have known how to take some things out
but it was still fun.
Right?
And
also
what else is there?
Mm.
Also
mm.
Ah,
we
went over everything starting from Rewind
so
right.
For the most part
we
tried not to end up in Supersonic's ending position and go straight into Like You Better
so it can keep connecting after Supersonic
and move right out to the extended stage
from Like You Better's formation
to do Love Disaster
and from Love Disaster
we tried hard to keep things flowing
without breaking the momentum
for Flover too.
Mm.
What else is there?
We should talk about Skyrunner now right?
For Skyrunner
really
2 weeks ago
no not even 2 weeks it was a week and a half ago that
the choreography was finished.
And
the dancers
literally
went on stage with it
in less than a week.
They are seriously amazing. Our dancer unnies
though they aren't unnies
the dancers are seriously amazing. Really right?
Because
what we did before
before Skyrunner
was just coming out while doing Fly High
but since we wanted this
to have a cheerleading choreography
we felt there needed to be
a thumping intro
right before it
to fit the cheerleading moves.
So I gave that suggestion
and they understood it perfectly
and the company produced
an intro for us. But that
took a while.
For the Skyrunner intro to come out.
So
since the song needed to be ready
for the choreography to be made
because the intro
took
a while
to come out
starting the Skyrunner choreography itself was a bit delayed.
But then the Skyrunner choreography came out
and it was so pretty
they set up all the formations
using the lift and everything
so it was really pretty. But while it was pretty
in terms of the members' needs
we wanted
a cheerleading choreography
that felt like
wow did they really come to do cheerleading?
We had that opinion.
But right at that time
our director teacher
had to step out
for a business trip
so she wasn't there.
But this opinion came up
while the teacher was away
and we had no time.
We really had no time.
So we were like what do we do? What do we do?
So I asked the unnies
what about
this kind of dance? I stood up and showed them a vibe like this
asking if this was what they wanted and the unnies
said oh that's good
so
they told me to try making it.
So
I really
stayed up until 6 AM
even though I had to wake up at 9 AM the next day
watching all kinds of
cheerleading choreography
from college
cheerleaders
cheerleading choreography
clubs
and cheerleading competitions
to American cheerleaders
I really watched it all
trying to figure out what would be
less difficult
but still look impressive
and really
click with people.
It had to have a definite cheerleading feel
but since we didn't have much time left
it had to be easy
to memorize
and repetitive
but
still cool
I had to consider all of this.
What could it be?
And since
I had to teach it I had to memorize it too.
At home
I set this up in front of me
and kept dancing by myself
with the AC
turned down to 18 degrees
on strong wind.
Honestly at home
I never lower it
below 24 or 25 degrees.
But I set it to 18 degrees
and danced all alone
learning
memorizing and learning from YouTube
taking videos of myself
thinking oh this looks good
and putting it together like that.
I made a few good versions
for the chorus
like versions 1 2
and 3
to have the unnies choose.
That's how I prepared it by the next day.
So the next day
with the unnies
we went over it
I think we finished this last week?
Ah
today is Monday so it must have been the week before last.
Was it around Wednesday?
At that time
Hayoung unnie and Nakko unnie
had a schedule so they got off work first.
It was just Jiwon
and Chaeng left
so I shared
the ideas
I had
telling them
there's this option and that option.
We have option 1 option 2 option 3
pick from these.
Which one is better?
So the three of us put our heads together to expand on
the frame I made
combining the unnies' ideas too
we all brainstormed together
and finished it.
After finishing it
we sent it to the teacher
because she needed to figure it out for the dancers too.
We sent it
and the next day
since Chaeng and Jiwon already learned it we had to teach Hayoung and Nakko unnies.
So then I
taught them.
I told Hayoung and Nakko to stay
and I taught them
but Hayoung unnie and
Nakko unnie had
new opinions again.
Since they had new opinions
ah
then
let's ask
everyone when all the members are here.
The next day
I gathered all the members
went to Chaeng and Jiwon and told them about the new ideas.
Then the unnies said doing this way is good and that way is good too.
Then I went back to Hayoung and Nakko asking what about this way what about that way?
I talked to everyone
coordinated it well
Then I went back to Hayoung and Nakko asking what about this way what about that way?
and we made it.
Skyrunner.
So
this was a group decision.
The final final
real final
seriously
something like that.
final
And after Skyrunner
we did Screen Time
on Day 1.
For Day 1
originally
the plan was to stay
in our designated spots
according to the formation
but since we don't use
free formations
in the main show
and some members
were just stuck
on one side
of the wings
we thought it would be nice
for all the members
to show their faces
to the audience
on both sides.
So that idea came up
and we decided
to just roam around freely.
And walking to the back while turning around
the director said
it would look really good
and it really
looked so good.
And
what else is there?
Things I suggested.
For Cold Blooded Chaeng unnie and
the teachers
stayed back
to make the choreography and teach us
so
props to Chaeng unnie for that.
Wow Chaeng unnie really
made the choreography so intense. It was so hard.
Ah it was
just
so exhausting again.
And for me
how should I say this?
When it comes to dancing
rather than putting a lot of strength
into my body
I feel more confident
doing dances that emphasize smooth lines.
So
since it was
a genre
of dance I hadn't really tried before
I really felt
awkward looking in the mirror at first
but I worked hard.
Ah really.
And
Blue Heart.
For Blue Heart
during the intro
the
members suggested
letting the siren sound ring out a bit more before starting the song.
Was it good?
But thinking about it
the siren sound
sounded a lot like a police car.
Right?
So
for Blue Heart
since
our outfits were black
we thought let's be thieves.
So
we asked the director
if it was possible
that while hearing the siren sound
we could
have lights searching the audience
like
police officers
using flashlights
to catch a thief.
Using lighting
to create that vibe and then
when the song starts
it turns out our members
are the culprits.
The culprits
who stole
Blue Heart.
Explaining it like that
we wanted the vibe of
'we found them'
so
a circular spotlight
would shine
right on
each member one by one.
So while searching the audience
'here they are they were on stage'.
We wanted the lighting to feel like that.
But even though we are the culprits
we'd walk out
feeling really confident
like
yeah it's us so what.
And they executed it so well it was so great.
For Teacher
Jiwon unnie and Hayoung unnie especially when Jiwon unnie was writing it
they wanted it
to have
a sexy choreography
using the hips
and everything.
With that in mind
since it was a song made like that
Jiwon unnie gave a lot of ideas for it
and the choreography
came out so pretty didn't it? For Teacher.
Ah for Blue Heart
yesterday at the party
with the
director
teacher
we were eating and talking and she told me.
She actually told me when we were learning the choreography too.
That
her favorite part in this entire concert
is my part. Here.
I really love this part
too. This
part.
Seriously
the teachers and the staff members
all said
this part
feels like a real killing part.
Yeah.
I
told them I'll keep doing my best.
I kept saying that.
Even my friends
and
my hometown
friend
the one hometown friend
who came
she
usually doesn't say things like this at every concert
but she told me
that part
and the gestures there were so cool.
You know how it feels
when you get acknowledged by an old friend
it feels really good.
She actually
brought it up first so I felt so good.
And the choreography for Eternal
came out so well right.
Honestly
some of you might know
but I was a bit awkward
with the b-side track Eternal.
I was a bit distant from it.
It's good but
it didn't really feel like my style
but the choreography came out so pretty
that now I'm totally
hooked on Eternal.
Chaeng unnie wanted it to really feel like a musical
and she said that since we were making the setlist.
Honestly
for Eternal
I couldn't really picture
how a musical vibe would look for it
but
just like Chaeng unnie said
the grand feeling was expressed so well in the choreography.
Especially the outro
came out so pretty.
And Pocket Treat.
It's my
absolute favorite choreography this time.
Seriously
my favorite.
Because we kept
doing cool things
and kept doing how should I say this?
these intense
sections
as soon as we got to Pocket Treat
I felt like I could finally breathe.
Just
Even before
it was
my type of song but with Pocket Treat
anyway
when a choreography draft comes out
the members
see it and find parts that are lacking
so we usually
receive various drafts and mix them together
but for Pocket Treat this time
as soon as we saw it
everyone
clapped and said
let's go with this right away so it was the very first choreography
we learned
for this concert.
The very first draft.
Because it was so pretty.
But you know what's crazy? The teacher is younger than me.
The choreography teacher is younger than me
and
this was
her first time
ever
making choreography.
Ah
she told me that yesterday at the wrap party. So I told her
the Pocket Treat choreography
is so pretty it's my favorite.
And she said
it was her first time making one.
You are a genius.
Seriously
keep doing it. Please
keep
keeping going.
So
I was like let's go. We kept talking like that and
really
Pocket Treat
isn't it so pretty?
It really is
so pretty.
The outro is pretty too. There isn't a single unpretty part
in Pocket Treat.
I'll never forget the happiness I felt
when I first saw
that choreography draft.
Meeting a choreography that
perfectly captured
a song I love so much.
I feel like a
Pocket Treat
promotional ambassador. Seriously please
listen to Pocket Treat. Give Pocket Treat lots of love. Why does everyone only like Teacher and Blue Heart
and not Pocket Treat?
I really love Pocket Treat so much.
I really
during Pocket Treat
really loved
being able to use
how should I say this?
I loved being able to use my facial expressions.
I mean
somehow
ah
it felt
a bit
less cringey to me.
It felt good to just
act super cute with all my heart.
Because I could pretend to be pretty.
Oh and then
what was it?
That
part of Chaeng unnie
when she walks out you know.
Na-ttan-tta
The part where she does that
it was there that
the teacher said before
ah
seeing this part made her realize
Jiwon likes
this kind of thing.
But for the main show
instead of doing a choreography
this time
for Wonderland and
Merry Go Round
ending it
just by singing
the song
was a first for us
but it had a great vibe and felt really nice.
First of all the background was so pretty.
Wonderland is
such a good song.
Ah,
that
repeating
'Your eyes'
was
Chaeng's idea.
Chaeng is
the one who suggested it.
I mean
we all had similar thoughts
about doing 'It's You' for the encore anyway
and
doing it multiple times
but nobody thought we'd do it
that many times.
Nobody expected it.
We thought we'd do it maybe three or four times
and be done with it because
when you look at other artists
doing encores
they give
a signal and
when the song comes on
it's mostly a song to jump around to.
It's not usually a song you actually have to belt out.
But for us
'It's You' is a song where you really have to sing.
Jiwon unnie and
Hayoung unnie lost their voices. By the end
Jiwon unnie was having a hard time.
Even with the ad-libs.
The ad-libs weren't even
laid out on the track.
They weren't on the backtrack so she really sang them
totally live
which is amazing.
Our main vocal unnie.
She didn't get scolded though. We told Chaeng she did a good job
and after it ended
when we went back to the waiting room we said it was so fun and she did great.
We even talked about doing it again.
Flover
when was your favorite part?
Ah we also got new custom mics this time.
Honestly when I saw it in person my mic was a bit
underwhelming.
The unnies' mics just looked prettier to me.
So I kind of
regretted
not doing it differently because
I chose an irregular pattern. I wanted it to sparkle more on stage
so when I asked how to make it sparkle more on stage
they said
placing the cubics
irregularly
makes it sparkle more so I went with an irregular pattern.
I did it.
But
the unnies did it in a regular pattern.
But regular
when you look at it in person the regular pattern is much
cleaner and
prettier.
So
really that
run-through
practice
in the practice room
when we were doing the run-through
I was like
I shouldn't have done this
ah I shouldn't have.
I shouldn't have made it irregular
ah can I take this off and redo it? Or do I have to buy a new one?
Ah this is expensive. This
is all I could think about. Really
my
Because
it's not a cheap price.
It's not a cheap price so I
regretted it so much.
Ah
when I
do something
I have to do it properly.
Because
if I really
do it carelessly
it won't work out guys.
Even with these in-ears
they're still perfectly fine so look at me still wearing them without changing. The exact same ones.
For several years.
Anyway
they're still perfectly fine so look at me still wearing them without changing. The exact same ones.
I really
so when doing the hand mics this time I looked up how so many artists
do it
what kind of mics they use and took screenshots of everything
compared them all
and thought oh this looks like this on stage and under certain lighting it looks a bit
unappealing. In photos
it looks like this but in videos it looks pretty and things like that.
So I didn't want that to happen
so I
checked everything
and
even
went into custom mic
accounts
to
see how they did it
and looked at other artists
like
photos
that the fans of other artists
took
for other artists
at their
concerts or
event photos
and videos
while looking at them
I also saw how they used them at award shows and places like that
and compared everything
thinking ah this one would be the prettiest.
With my
with my image
and everything combined I think white would suit me
and
sparkles on stage
would look pretty so
I should put cubics
on it. But cubics
I didn't think that far but cubics were also very diverse. White
cubics.
So from there I
asked for the prettiest one
the most popular one. That's what I did
but then I
kept thinking I made a mistake during practice.
So
ah I should've just
like Jiwon unnie
gone with a clean metal. Safely.
So
ah I should've just done metal.
Ah
or maybe there are lots of matte ones
these days too.
I should've done matte white.
Ah just
silver
or white
that
kind of glass-like white
that was
originally one of my choices too.
I kept thinking ah I should've just done that
but on stage it was actually pretty.
So I felt good again. Guys
I don't think I need to buy it again. I was seriously debating whether to buy it again.
But on stage
with the LED screen
and fans
looking at the photos our Flover took for us
it looked pretty.
I don't think I need to change it.
I think it'll be fine.
My mood got better again.
The mics are
at the company. Not at our house.
They have to be handled so carefully.
And really
as some of you may know it's been a really long time since I wore this
mic
I wore it.
This Shure
DPA
I only used the ones that stick close like this
but
that
session
needed to look cool so
I put up with the discomfort of Shure
and
ended up using Shure.
Shure
is really uncomfortable.
Shure too
feels very different. Ah the sound quality is much better but
uh
when dancing
or performing
hair
gets caught
inside or
when doing gestures all these things we wear here get
blocked or
when using them on the face
and when putting them on and off
really hair
it keeps catching hair like this
so obviously
for concerts
especially
we have to do quick changes really fast
but the discomfort of quick changes too
but
I did it for the style
entirely
for it
But during Skyrunner
when
that
obviously when we did the run-through
we didn't
pop these.
We didn't pop the confetti
during Skyrunner
at our first show
all the members
the thing we talked about at the first concert was
how happy we were during Skyrunner
the confetti
coming out there
none of us knew about it.
Only the director knew. The director really is
a genius.
How could they shoot out confetti right there
ah really
so
they timed it right when we go hey hey hey
and the red
and yellow confetti popped.
Seeing that I felt so
good so during the first
first concert
then
that
the second and third concert too Skyrunner was so fun
and
exciting but
nothing compares to the first concert
where our real facial expressions came out
like that.
Our expressions came out so genuinely
it was so funny.
Something about this
and the choreography I really
like
this choreography
what is it?
that jumping and
turning like this
turning
ladan
tang tang tang
this is so good. This
this choreography is my absolute favorite
choreography. During Skyrunner
doing it like this and turning
and turning
all the way
this is my ultimate favorite choreography
so doing it was so much fun.
Why did I cry
during the middle concert?
The middle
concert
I think I looked pretty
the members
all
I feel like
the middle concert
is when the members look the prettiest.
I feel this
every concert but
the middle concert
is the most
pretty.
There's a reason for this.
Well
the reason the middle concert is the prettiest is
it's still less tiring.
It's still somewhat
okay. Bearable.
And
we still have some stamina left.
And so our faces are less exhausted. The dark circles
haven't come down as much.
So our faces
still have some
liveliness to them.
And
uh the lighting or
things like that
at the first concert
we look at the monitor and
point out things that were lacking
and give feedback
during the feedback time after the first concert
point out things that were lacking
and give feedback
during the feedback time after the first concert
we give a little bit of feedback.
So we adjust things according to that feedback for the second concert.
And for the second concert
based on the first concert
our makeup routine
is also adjusted for the second concert.
Uh like here
depending on the lighting here
the color of
the blush washes out. At this part
the
colors come out too strong. Here
these
black
colors come out a bit too dark so
we should tone down the black colors. We talk about things like this.
We can check these things through the monitor
so all the feedback is applied for the middle concert.
So
the middle
concert
is the most
pretty. But the last concert
then from the middle concert
couldn't you do even more feedback?
We have to try something new for the last concert.
It has to be different from the middle concert.
So
if we perform for three days all three days
have to show
a different side of us
if we perform for three days all three days
so for the middle concert
we make up for what we lacked
at
the first concert.
So it looked pretty.
Matching that prettiness for the third day
we try something new. For the third day
uh
we do a different hairstyle
and
we do things like that.
And
for the final concert
there's a slight
slight bit of
exhaustion on our faces
just a bit
present.
Next time we
should
maybe
do two days. Two days
do two days and
take a two-week break?
How about it?
Three days in a row is
a bit
three days in a row is a bit
We say this
every time but
it's tiring.
Especially this
concert
required a lot of stamina so
at the first concert I
really danced like it was rehearsal. I gave it my all just like in rehearsal.
But
I should just tie my hair. It keeps bothering me.
So
during the first concert
I kind of
thought of the outfit
like a run-through
run-through
and put a lot of energy into it
just like in practice
and run-throughs
but I didn't think about
the variable of the outfits.
The outfits were
so tight
especially the white outfit
how should I say it? It's a one-piece dress.
A one-piece dress
with cubics attached and it's a white
color.
White makes you look bulky so easily.
There are cubics attached. It sparkles right?
If it sparkles
it's even easier to look bulky.
Because of that
it's a one-piece dress
and
there's no skin
showing at all. It's not a crop top
if it were a crop top
the skin would at least break up the outfit
but since it wasn't like that
it's
easy for the body
to look
bulky so
when wearing that kind of one-piece dress I try to hold it
in as tightly
as possible like this.
I hold it in tight.
But
when
practicing
I wear slightly loose
clothes to dance so
when using my breath and things like that
there's no discomfort.
There's no difference but
at the first show
when I try to inhale the air needs to reach
my lungs but
it couldn't reach them.
Wow
I shouldn't go this hard. If I perform
this intensely
with full power
and dance
it wouldn't work I realized this at the first show.
So
I just
sat down.
Up there
I kept
sitting down
to stabilize
my breathing.
So I was sitting down
that's what happened so you don't have to worry too much guys.
Yeah.
So from the middle concert onwards
I
controlled my pacing well between strong and weak
But
even up to the middle concert
wow
it was
so exhausting. That white outfit
Actually
it was harder than the second session
with Cold Blooded. The white
The one
with Attitude and
Prom Night
and those
other ones
those three songs
were honestly way harder than
the Cold Blooded and Attitude session for me.
I really
thought that part was the hardest.
So wow
I still think so and consider that part the hardest
so it was like that until the middle and then for the final concert
my body
adjusted so it was fine again
as expected humans are creatures of adaptation guys right? This
one-piece dress
is really hard to wear
people who wear
one-piece dresses really have a hard time.
So having a one-piece as a stage outfit is truly
a difficult thing.
But
the
person who said she would wear the one-piece dress is me.
I did that.
Why did I do that?
But it was so pretty.
I really think
that stage outfit is so
pretty right?
I told them
I wanted to go with
a one-piece dress
and the director made it so beautifully.
Even
when I did the fitting
they brought the waist in
like
a lot
so it
fit my body like this. When doing the fitting
I said oh I think you can take it in a bit more.
In about two weeks I'll probably lose a bit more weight.
So
with that in mind I think you can take it in a bit more. That's what I said
and because of that
I got greedy because I wanted to look pretty.
Airplane Mode behind the scenes?
It was so confusing.
Really
Airplane Mode
is so hard and
so confusing
I honestly practiced that
every single day. Airplane Mode
I couldn't get used to it.
My grandparents came this time you know.
So my maternal grandparents came
and I almost
teared up a little.
And it was also so cute.
I made it
I made it. So
I could see them. I didn't even know where they were but
when I
looked over
it said Jiheon
on their phone like this
and my grandparents were waving it around.
Along with my mom and dad.
It's so cute right?
And anyone could tell
uh
people of my grandparents' age
it could only be my grandparents. Only my grandparents were there.
So I didn't even know where they were sitting but
as soon as
I saw them I was so
happy and
during the encore I got a little
what should I say?
lost in thought.
I really got slightly lost in thought.
I invited
my grandparents
way too late.
I should have invited them sooner.
It was my grandparents' first time coming.
Honestly
coming all the way up to Seoul
from the countryside
isn't easy
because even this time
my grandparents came up
on the day of the concert and went right back down on the same day
and yesterday
I heard they had a really hard time on their way back so yesterday
coming here
I was worrying a lot
but still
my grandma
liked it so much and
my grandpa
seemed to like it a lot too.
In my grandparents' eyes they only saw me.
What's so cute is that
I called them after
and we
met up and my grandparents
mom and dad were heading home
but the road
out was jammed with cars
so since they are
elderly I thought it would be hard for them
uh
a bit
to leave through our exit
or
if they were still stuck in traffic
I wanted to let my grandparents
leave first
so I called them
but my grandparents
were so
happy
they said it was so great
and that I was the prettiest
you're the prettiest
our Jiheon is the prettiest they told me this
so I felt really good.
So honestly
this Chuseok
ah
I barely have any days off
so this Chuseok
uh
I was debating whether to see my mom and dad
by
going down there
or just asking them to come up here
or
should I just rest alone at home?
Ah I'll just invite them all next year I had this kind of thought
but then
I realized I shouldn't do that. After seeing my grandparents like this
uh
I felt like I had to go down immediately
so I have to go down.
Why
am I
not from Seoul?
I
really feel this the most
during Seollal.
Wow
people from Seoul must have it so good.
That's exactly when I think Seoul people have it so good.
Going down and
coming back up is so exhausting
right.
Man
like
when I listen to my friends
who live in Seoul
hey during Chuseok
hey what are you doing for Chuseok they ask me this
and I'm like
uh
I have to go to my hometown
like this
I have to go to my hometown and see my grandparents and when I say that
yeah
everyone is kinda like
yeah exactly
but does it take that long? I live in the countryside you know. So
when they say then you're not going
ah
I mean
going in the morning and
meeting up for lunch was what I meant they say.
Ah
so in the morning
you eat with your family
and then
from lunchtime or evening you can hang out. For you guys
that's how it is. You Seoul people.
For us
it takes hours to go down
hours to go down
we go down and
meet up with mom and dad
go to Jeju Island once
sleep for a night
and then the next day
go to my maternal grandma's house
and
sleep another night
and my grandma's house is also
doesn't she live in Suncheon?
We have to go again. Since she's in Jeonbuk
we have to drive from Jeonbuk
for an hour or two
and
greet everyone
me
like this
Whether I sleep over or
go straight
to my parents' house, my hometown
and then
sleep a night there
before coming back up to Seoul
Chuseok is already over.
That's how my Chuseok used to be.
Ah but it was always like that for me even when I was a baby living in Suncheon. In Suncheon
my school friends
all had their grandparents living right there in Suncheon.
If not Suncheon then places like Gwangyang
or Yeosu.
They were all living within a 30 or 40 minute
driving distance.
As for me
they would always just meet up and play among themselves.
While I had to go all the way to Jeju Island
and do all that.
But
thinking about it now
I wish my grandparents
were the type who could just gather everyone
in one place
but they lived
too far away
and scattered all over.
But
honestly
since my grandparents all
lived in different
provinces
I definitely got that
provincial, how should I say this? That countryside
vibe when going there.
When I go to my
grandparents' house
there's this warm village
ready to
welcome me
and
I just love the rice paddies and fields.
Jeju Island
doesn't have rice paddies
or regular fields though.
When you go to my grandmother's house
and
go up to
the roof
you can see a really wide open view.
There you have
clotheslines and things like that
and I would
hang on them like pull-up bars
and play with my younger cousins.
And
if you look there
on that roof
there's another
building-like structure
and on the side of it
there are marks
where my cousins and I
measured our heights
since we were babies.
It shows how tall we were in what year at what age
and it wasn't even drawn with a marker
but scratched in with a stone
so it's a bit faded.
So every time we go we add a little more
and draw it in.
And as for my maternal grandmother's house
every time I go
it feels like
the house has leveled up somehow.
Since my grandparents
used to do
farming
there's this huge
warehouse and
a massive
freezer that's
bigger than the house itself.
In the
grandmother's house
yard
they have
tractors and those
what are they called? Tractors? Those
big vehicles.
And for farming
they have those machines that go
rattle rattle
and
plant
things
not the cultivators
but the ones my grandfather
sits
really high up on
and when he drives it
these
big
wheels
move and
plant the rice seedlings.
And there's also a motorcycle and stuff
like that.
And
if the house is here there's that warehouse and in front of it
is that giant freezer.
In that freezer
there's food
grown from the small field
my grandmother tends near the parking lot
or things
my grandmother makes
since she makes such huge portions
like kimchi.
Well kimchi isn't in the freezer
but anyway there's a lot of food in there.
My
maternal grandparents
are seriously
the stereotypical grandparents you would imagine.
They make massive portions
and
their food
is delicious.
Because
my Jeju grandmother
doesn't really like cooking.
She gets along well with my mom
with their mindset of
just making enough food
for what we need
and buying side dishes instead.
But my
maternal grandmother
makes so much food
that my mom scolds her every day.
Mom please
stop doing that.
So
when making kimchi
she always
makes a massive amount
and maybe that's why
her food is seriously so good.
Because
even the village people
all
acknowledge it.
There were even people
who wanted to
buy her kimchi
even though we don't sell it
they just
wanted to
pay for it
so badly
so a lot of people bought it.
It's really good but nowadays since my grandmother
is getting older her taste buds have changed a bit
so the seasoning is stronger than before
but seriously
her dongchimi is
insane guys.
It's really
oh seriously
Do you guys know about this?
My grandmother's house
still had that going on.
It's gone now since
they put a cold storage warehouse there.
After the freezer
was built
it disappeared but
in Jeollabuk-do
when winter comes
it snows so much at my grandmother's house.
In the yard
the big clay pots
get buried into the ground
and the kimchi
or dongchimi
inside those pots
are all stacked in the yard
and snow piles up on them.
Then I would tell my grandmother
Grandma
I want to drink
Then I would tell my grandmother
Grandma
and eat dongchimi
I want to drink
and she would
go outside
brush off the snow
pull it open
and pour me some dongchimi.
The kimchi
that comes out of there is seriously amazing.
Flovers
As soon as my grandmother
pulls it up
I have to eat it right away.
She rips it out from there like this
and it's so delicious.
And
oh when I went recently for Seollal
there was a flower greenhouse
at her house too.
In that tiny space
in the yard
she managed to squeeze in
a flower greenhouse so now there's no space.
With two huge warehouses already
there wasn't really enough room
for a flower greenhouse too
but she squeezed
the flowers in there anyway.
So
my mom scolded her a lot asking why she did that.
But my grandfather
yelled back at her saying if grandma wants it
why does it matter.
Yeah
because my grandparents
are totally
like a dating couple.
They're so in love
all lovey-dovey.
Every day
when my grandmother
goes to get her nails done my grandfather always tags along
and stays right by her side.
Whether it's her nails
or
accessories and things like that
my grandfather always buys them for her every day.
They're totally dating.
My grandparents
are so cute.
And as for the parking lot
if you look at it
it's not
like a real parking lot
with a roof
but across from her house
there's a big space
to park
and my grandfather
heard my grandmother
say she wanted to drive.
My grandmother
is seriously cool. She even rides
a motorcycle.
But
whenever they were together
my grandfather would drive
so she brought up wanting a car
to drive when she goes out alone.
I guess she just mentioned it in passing
but my grandfather
seriously
bought her a car
that neither my mom dad nor I had ever owned.
Since they are elderly
they probably just wanted the best one.
The person
selling it probably said this one is the best
and introduced them
to the most expensive car.
But from the perspective of my parents and me
they are almost always
together every day
so it seemed like
they would hardly use it.
They probably won't ride it much.
And since
my grandmother
is getting older
her vision
isn't as clear
as it used to be.
So
she doesn't even drive much anyway
but because of something
she just said in passing
they bought it and eventually
that car
got locked up
in a greenhouse they built specifically for it.
It just fits that car perfectly
and can't even come out.
That car
is just in storage.
That's why I asked them to give it to me.
I said if you aren't going to use it give it to me Grandpa but grandma said no to that.
Seriously
my grandfather is so cute.
Anyway I was so happy they came and showed us this time.
Plus it's my grandmother's birthday soon
so it feels like
he gave her a huge birthday present.
But she wants another birthday gift too.
I didn't even say anything but as soon as I mentioned her upcoming birthday
she was like
I don't need
I didn't even say anything but as soon as I mentioned her upcoming birthday
a big bag
just give me a small one.
A small one is fine.
I hadn't said a word.
I never said I was buying her anything.
I hadn't even thought about what to buy her yet.
But she said that.
I asked Grandma do you want a bag I thought you said no last time
and she was like
well
if you're going to buy one
buy that one.
Oh so
you prefer a bag over pocket money I asked.
And she said
oh then pocket money is better.
I found it
so funny seriously.
Sorry but I can't afford to put pocket money inside a bag for you
I can't
do that much
but someday
I definitely will.
To my grandparents.
The horror experience story
that's pretty much it guys.
The horror experience
was like that.
My friends contacted me.
Hey at least
you handled it well.
Because I played an escape room
game with my friends once.
When I played with them
it wasn't even a horror experience or horror escape room.
It wasn't a horror escape room
but I just hated the vibe so much
because it was dark
and
I was already freaking out from being so scared
and suddenly
someone solved something while we were all scattered
and I was sticking so close to one person
going hey I'm scared
when on the other side
one of the kids
did it.
Right then
the thing in front of me
that was
closed just popped open
with a bang. I was seriously
seriously
so the kids were like this was better
than that time.
Because even the kids back then
saw me and thought wow she is totally beyond saving
so they never
brought up doing escape rooms
again.
Ah but
our director
and PD
as well as our company staff
were all against
doing the horror one.
Since they know how scared I get
and especially
our current
manager unnie
has been with us for about 8
actually 9 years now
so she knows us and me so well
that she kept
saying no we can't do that
but since
Flovers really wanted to see a horror experience
and wanted the members to do it
I was like alright
let's give it a try
and
that's how we did it.
But then
it went exactly as expected.
So even now when I talk about it I feel like crying.
Let's not talk about
the horror experience
anymore.
The swimming pool
was fun.
Also you guys know I love riding amusement park rides.
So
I really liked the swimming pool.
Was I okay after getting hit by the barrel?
Whoa.
The bruise is all gone now so
it's fine.
As long as we didn't get hurt that's all that matters.
Actually
the part where I was begging
not to do the horror experience
saying I really couldn't do it
was originally edited out.
It was cut and they were just
how should I put it? Just um
going to upload it saying
I couldn't participate
but I thought it might not look good.
I felt like
if that part wasn't included
it wouldn't be convincing to show how scared I really was
and how
serious I was about it.
I thought I needed to
show that somehow
or else
I'd probably get a lot of hate
so
even though it might be uncomfortable to watch
I felt like it had to be
included.
Because only then
would I
get less
hate.
If I just sat out
I'd just be someone who bailed.
So
I'm really glad the members
did it so well and made it fun instead.
Anyway
ah
I really wish we could do the concert
for just one more week right?
Concerts are so fun.
Why are they seriously so fun?
It's so much fun.
For this concert
the members really
put a lot of
thought into
the goods and
tried hard to
prepare everything
so I'm so proud
but
since Flovers loved it so much we are very
proud of
that.
The windbreaker is so pretty.
Isn't Chaeyoung unnie seriously a genius.
Chaeyoung unnie shared a lot of ideas
on how she wanted it
to be done.
Now I think I should slowly
get going.
I only have 7%
left.
My phone
battery only has 7% left.
Honestly
this concert was one where
all the members
worked really hard
practicing until
dawn
to make it fun for
everyone who came
so seeing Flovers
like it makes me feel
even better and makes it
more meaningful since we participated in it.
The members also
gave the idea to make the VCR
feel like a variety show
and I was so thankful
that you guys
loved all of it so much this time.
You know?
I still have a lot of concert videos
I want to upload
but I guess I'll have to
upload them tomorrow.
I should upload them tomorrow.
Anyway great job
on this Monday
everyone
and sleep well.
Bye.